Yamaha renowned for
building quarter million dollar grand piano is used
in legendary concert Halls worldwide has spent the
last eight years developing their latest and also
their most affordable weighted 88 keys digital
piano keyboard their outgoing model the p45 which
I reviewed on my channel was immensely popular
Po and always out of stock due to its package
of affordable price great sound quality and key
action in the last couple of years the competition
such as Roland Casio alices and Donna has caught
up with Yamaha when it comes to budget piano
keyboards I should know better than anyone I've
made more than 500 piano keyboard reviews on my
channel
[Music] will this new piano keyboard get Yamaha
back in the game to find out I use my own money
paid full retail price here's the receipt
and bought myself one you're most welcome
come along with me as I investigate the key
action sound quality build quality features
and functionality of the p145 yamaha's latest
and most affordable 88 weighted Keys digital
piano keyboard and see how it Compares
with similarly priced offerings from the
competition
you can find a full specifications and the
best price for this together with my list of
recommended keyboards pianos and music apps
in the description the most important thing
on a weighted keyboard is the key action
specifically how how close does it feel
to a traditional acoustic piano the GHC
AKA graded Hammer compact key action is a
definite Improvement on the p145 compared to
the data ghs action in the model it replaces
the action is a little firmer quicker
with a progressive key waiting across
the octaves however to achieve a more compact
Chassy depth Yamaha has noticeably shortened
the key pivots which at Von kenis will have
issues with when playing between the Black
Keys
Yamaha has chosen to continue using glossy black
and white keys when most of the competition has
gone for a lightly textured key surface for
more traction which I personally prefer as I
live in the humid Tropics I'm surprised
that Yamaha hasn't upd anti with triple
key sensors and escapement simulation which
is important for playing and ornaments check
my video description where for a similar price
you can get an 88 weighted keyboard that has
a noticeably better key action with longer key
pivots textured key surface triple key sensors
and escapement [Music] simulation [Music] the
sound most buyers will use 99% of the time on
this keyboard is the default piano sound and it
doesn't disappoint the piano voice is sampled
from yamaha's $150,000 cf3s concert grand piano
still used in many conservatories the base notes
are thick and Rich while the higher notes
are bright it's an unmistakable Yamaha sound
[Applause] [Music]
you get a total of 10 voices on
this keyboard two grand pianos two
electric pianos two pipe organs hopsy cord
accordion strings and de a Chinese bamboo
flute
yamaha's choice and number of onboard voices
left me scratching my head similarly priced
competitors offer more than 30 highquality
voices versus just 10 on this keyboard a
jazz organ and a double base instead of two
pipe organs and the accordion would make this
keyboard significantly more sty the inclusion
of the Chinese flute is also evidence that the
China Market is so powerful that Yamaha has to
acknowledge it while the voices can be [Music]
layered and the volume of the Dual
voices can be balanced there is no
option to split the keyboard with different voices
on the right and left website which in
number of the competition can [Music]
do
[Music]
what left me disappointed is Yamaha didn't take
the opportunity to increase the note polyany on
this keyboard while similarly priced 88 key
weighted keyboards from the competition have
96 note pany this keyboard has just 64 for
beginner piano students 64 note Pony is fine
however the low pony means that Yamaha is not able
to offer more complex and Nuance sample textures
such as string resonance and key off resonance
which the competition offers the p145 offers
only damper resonance which is pretty standard
on digital pianos these [Music] days [Music]
[Music]
a basic pedal is in included with this keyboard
but you are better off getting the optional single
or triple pedal unit which supports half
pedaling soft and sofo like a traditional
acoustic grand piano link to these two pedals
in the description thankfully Yamaha did upgrade
the sound system on the p145 It Now Sports
a pair of 7 Watts amplifiers firing through
a four speaker setup which makes the sound
output noticeably punchier and louder than
many of the competition which uses an anemic
two speaker setup check the video description
for my recommended piano that has way more
voices and more pany for a similar [Music]
prize
for silent practice there is a quarter
inch headphones Jack which doubles as an
audio output located at the rear I would
have preferred the headphones Jack to be
located just next to the player for easier
access which is what many other brands have
done while voices can be selected layered and
transposed by pressing the function button and
the corresponding key adjusting the volume to
balance the voice layers is clunk key and quick
Transportation on the Fly requires you to carry
along the function chart if you don't use Yamaha
smart pianis [Music] app while the smart pianis
app available on both IOS and Android is the
best in the industry with its intuitive fluid
and feature reach UI allowing users to select
C layer and balanc voices as well as record an
unlimited number of their performances for quick
sharing online the laof wireless Bluetooth
connectivity creates too much friction for
the user as you will have to use a compatible
USB cable to connect to your mobile [Music]
devices
[Music]
streaming backing tracks to play along
with also require a USB cable as there
is no wireless Bluetooth audio streaming
which most of the competition has I am
disappointed that Yamaha didn't use a
modern USBC Port like what many other
keyboards are using but kept their really
dated USB type B printer port [Music]
[Music] what thankfully the USB port supports both
midi and digital audio data with it built-in audio
interface which is perfect for use with music
learning apps the music learning apps I recommend
together with similarly priced keyboards with
wireless Bluetooth for unparalleled connectivity
and ease of use with music learning
apps can be found in the video [Music]
description
[Music] at just 10 kg the p45 is noticeably
lighter and more compact compared to its
predecessor and competition but sacrifices
had to be made such as the cold hard plastics
everywhere and the shortkey pivot one thing I
love is the redesigned music rest Which F and
looks more robust and from my tests the music
rest can definitely support huge fake and heavy
music books compared to the previous [Music]
[Applause] model unless Yamaha aggressively
Cuts pricing or you can get one during a sale
the 8 years Yamaha spent improving the worldly
popular p p45 is simply too little too
late the p45 isn't bad by any means but
the competition is better value and depending on
your psycho acoustic preference may sound better
too you can find my list of recommended keyboards
pianos and music apps in the [Music] description
my name is Jeremy C and I'll
see you in my next video